http://www.churchinwales.org.uk/en/privacy-notice/

Diocese
‘Diocese’ refers to the geographical territory in which a bishop exercises oversight. The Church in Wales is divided into six dioceses each with its own cathedral in which is housed the cathedra (the bishop’s ‘chair’ or ‘throne’).
Priest
‘Priest’ comes from the Greek word for ‘elder’. Priests in the Church in Wales are those authorised specifically to proclaim forgiveness of sins, preside at the Eucharist and bless God’s people, as well as other responsibilities.
Home
Privacy Notices
Privacy Notices
Church in Wales Data Protection Policies and Privacy NoticesThe Representative Body of the Church in Wales (“the RB”) uses personal information to carry out its many functions supporting the mission and ministry of the Church in Wales.The RB collects a wide range of personal data required for or incidental to the discharge of its functions, involving employees, clergy, pensions, housing, public consultations, recruitment and appointment, safeguarding, and so forth. The RB endeavours to ensure that this personal information is used in line with the expectations and interests of those with whom they come into contact, including their employees, office holders, members and the general public for the benefit of the Church and wider society and in compliance with all applicable data protection legislation.Privacy NoticesThe RB has prepared a General Privacy Notice which gives information on how your personal data is processed. The General Privacy Notice applies to most personal data processed by the RB and is applicable to clergy, former clergy, members, tenants of property owned by the RB, donors, users of our website, members of the Governing Body, individuals who contact us with enquiries or complaints, users of our website, individuals who feature in our newsletters or articles, individuals who we engage to provide services to us, individuals who engage with us on social media and individuals who undertake training courses with us.Additionally, there are separate Privacy Notices for members of the RB Staff Pension Scheme, students at St Padarn’s Institute and for data held by the Provincial Safeguarding Team.PoliciesThe RB and Bench of Bishops have published a policy relating to the data held on Clergy Personal Files, which includes details on the types of information stored, the location of the files, sharing and retention.The RB has also published a Data Protection Policy for employees, clergy, members of the RB, temporary and agency workers, other contractors, interns and volunteers, and a Data Retention Policy (which should be read alongside the retention policies set out in the relevant Privacy Notices and in the Clergy Personal File Guidance).Other Useful DocumentsThe RB has issued guidance on Sharing Personal Data and a form to assist an individual in making a Subject Access Request.The following documents are available to download:Church in Wales Data Protection Policy (Word)Clergy Personal Files Policy (Word)RB Data Retention Policy (Word)Subject Access Request Form (Word)Data Sharing Guidance (Word)Privacy NoticesGeneral Privacy Notice (Word)Staff Pension Scheme (Word)St Padarns Students (Word)Safeguarding Team Privacy Notice (Word)
Share
